# lan Matsumoto

## DATA SPECIALIST

## CONTACT



https://www.ianmats.com/



808-679-7230



ianmat55@gmail.com

## **PROFILE**

Ian Matsumoto is an analyst and aspiring software engineer. Traveling to the Bay Area from his hometown of Honolulu HI, Ian is pursuing his passion for creative innovation through a career in technology. He carries with him 5+ years of experience with GIS technologies, a love for computer science, and an exceptional work ethic.

## **EDUCATION**

# University of Redlands

Bachelor of Science (2015-2019)

Environmental Science

GIS

Mathematics

# **SKILLS**

#### Technologies:

Git

GIS based systems

#### Languages:

Python

SQL

HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Node

#### Professional:

QA processing

New hire training

Technical writing

Adaptability

Time management

Workflow documentation

# **WORK HISTORY**

## Data Specialist

Tesla | 10/2020 - present

Assist in the training and development of Tesla autopilot ai through the use of GIS and data labeling

- Served as a bottleneck of data labeling for six teams,
  identifying areas critical to training the neural network
- labled and verified an average of 100 data sets per day in a dynamic workflow
- Serve as a critical asset to the QA team and learned about the general workflow to QA process. Identify and resolve Quality Assurance workflow issues and improvement initiatives.
- Drive teams to improve processes, explicate data and yield meaningful metrics.
- Direct two daily feedback reports for engineering, project management, and leadership teams.
- Worked in dynamic environment helping with various teams and filling numerous roles under Tesla autopilot

## GIS Analyst

Apple via Apex Systems (Contract) | 07/2019 - 09/2020

Used GIS software to mark construction projects that would affect routing or address changes in Apple Maps

- Conduct web research on construction projects and track their progress through Apple's GIS software
- Responsible for updated and tracking maps in Riverside,
  San Bernardino, and Orange County
- Monitor traffic and pedestrian density on maps to identify areas of potential construction
- Communicate and collaborate with city/county officials, private companies and peers regarding new projects

# **PROJECTS**

# JobScraper.io

technologies | Node, Express, Postgresql, HTML/CSS/EJS

• Webscraper that scrapes linkedin, indeed and google jobs for listings that meet specified criteria. Built using Node/Express framework, ejs front end, and Postgresql database. Jobscraper.io was built to streamline my job searching process and also serve as a portfolio piece.

## **CLI Websocket Chatbot**

technologies | Python, Socket Communication

• In terminal chatroom utilizing socket and tcp communication. The multi-client server class inherits from the base client class, accepting other client connections and relaying data to all users in the room.

# Birthday Storage App

technologies | Flask, mySQL, HTML/CSS/JavaScript

• Flask CRUD application that stores friend's birthday and and name utilizing SQLite for a lightweight test application.